Good morning. I'd like to open a bank account, please.
Certainly. If you'd like to take a seat, I'll just get some details from you
It won't take long. Thanks.
Is it a current account or a deposit account you wanted? A current account.
Right. I've got the application form here then
We have different types. I see you've got our leaflet there.
I've decided on the one called 'Select.'
Right, that's fine, so, first of all, can I have your full name please?
Yes, it's Pieter Henes. That's P. I-E-T-E-R.
Is it H-E-double N-E-S?
Uh, only one N actually. It's a less common spelling of the name.
Oh, right. OK. And what's your date of birth please?
The twenty-seventh of the first, nineteen seventy-three.
Right. And will this be a joint account? No, just myself.
OK, fine. And where are you living, Mr. Henes? 15. Riverside.
Is that all one word? Yes. Exeter? Yes.
How long have you been at your present address? Er, is it more than two years?
Ah, just two weeks actually
I only arrived in the country a month ago. I'm from Holland.
Oh, that's fine. But we normally ask for a previous address in that case.
Oh yes, well, it's Rielsdorf 2. That's R. I-E-L-S-D-O-R-F 2, Utrecht.
Holland. OK. Thank you. Do you have a daytime telephone number?
Yes, I think the number at my office is six-oh-six-two-nine-five. Um, just a minute, I'd better check.
Oh no sorry, six- one-six. I'm not used to it yet
Would you like my home number too?
Yes please. It's seven-nine-six-four-three-one.
Are they both local numbers? Yes.
Right. And your occupation?
Well, I'm in Britain as a project manager, but that's not my main job
I'm an engineer by profession.
I see. I think I'll put that then. It's shorter
Now we usually ask for a piece of information
which we can use to check your identity, for security reasons
You know, if you phone us.
Like, erm, my wife's first name?
Mother's might be better. It's less likely to be known.
OK. Hers is Siti. Siti? Yes, S. I-T. I. It's Indonesian.
Fine. And how much would you like to open your account with?
We usually ask for a minimum sum of £50. That's about €75.
Well, I'm going to transfer €2,000 from my Dutch account, just till I get paid.
In fact, I wanted to ask you about that. What's the best way to do it?
It depends which bank you're with.
It's the Fransen Bank in Utrecht.
OK, fine. I'll check that in a minute
If we have links with them we can do a direct transfer.
But it's not a big problem either way. Um, let's see
How often would you like to receive statements?
I haven't really thought. Um, what's the usual thing?
It's up to you. Some people like them weekly.
Oh, no, that's too often. Can I have them sent, um, once a month?
Yes, that's fine. Is there anything else?
I was thinking of registering for your internet service at some stage.
Oh, yes. Would you like me to send you information about that? Please, yes.
And would you like to receive information about the bank's other services -
insurance, loans, anything like that?
Hmm, I don't think so, thanks.
That's OK then. And one last thing, if you agree...